Inventory of the Ginetta Sagan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Aurora Foundation, 1981-2002
  - Poland, 1981-2002
    - 1981-1986 (Box-folder 339: 1-2)
      Relates mainly to Solidarity and Zbigniew Romaszewski. Includes memoranda on Poland trips
    - 1987 (Box-folder 339: 3)
      Relates mainly to GS's trip to Poland and includes photographs and negatives of GS after car accident
    - 1989 (Box-folder 339: 4)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 339: 5)
      Includes photographs of human rights rally
    - 1991 (Box-folder 339: 6)
      Correspondence regarding her trip to Poland
    - 1994-1995 (Box-folder 339: 7)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 339: 8)
    - 2002, undated (Box-folder 339: 9)
      Includes notes by GS and letter from Romaszewski
    - Barbara Piasecka Johnson, 1986-2000 (Box-folder 339: 10-11)
      Includes travel diaries by LS
    - "A Stupid Way to Die," drafts by GS on her accident in Poland, 1987, undated (Box-folder 340: 1)
    - Zeszyty Literackie, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 340: 2)
      Grant agreements and correspondence on funding the journal
    - National Endowment for Democracy, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 340: 3-5)
  - Audit, 1987 (Box-folder 341: 1)
  - Ford Foundation, 1985 (Box-folder 341: 2)
  - MacArthur Foundation correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 341: 3)
  - Vietnam printed matter, 1979-1987 (Box-folder 341: 4)
- Video tapes, 1994, undated
  On VHS
  - "Isle of Elba/Brusson,", 1994 June (Box 341)
  - The "Matchbox Story" with Lidia, 1994 June (Box 341)
    Use copy reference number: 83017_v_0007591
    Part of the interview Ginetta Sagan did with Lidia Ghielmetti at the latter's home in Italy. In English. Duration 5:52.
  - Interview with Tiziana's father at a memorial for the resistance, undated (Box 341)
    In Italian
- Chronological files, 1983-1994
  Contains Aurora Foundation, Amnesty International, and personal correspondence
  - 1983 (Box-folder 342: 1)
  - 1984 (Box-folder 342: 2)
  - 1985 (Box-folder 342: 3)
  - 1986 (Box-folder 342: 4)
  - 1987 (Box-folder 342: 5)
  - 1988 (Box-folder 342: 6)
  - 1989 (Box-folder 342: 7)
  - 1990 (Box-folder 343: 1)
  - 1991 (Box-folder 343: 2)
  - 1992 (Box-folder 343: 3)
  - 1993 (Box-folder 343: 4)
  - 1994 (Box-folder 343: 5)
- Printed matter, 1970s-2000 (Box-folder 343: 6)
  - The Greek Case, Report of the Commission, Volume 1, Part 2, Council of Europe, European Commission of Human Rights, 1970s (Box-folder 344: 1)
  - Forging an Intelligence Partnership: CIA and the Origins of the BND, 1945-1949, edited by Kevin C. Ruffner, CIA History Staff, Center for the Study of Intelligence, Vols. I and II, 1999 (Box-folder 344: 2)
  - Retour à Erfurt: 1935-1945: récit d'une jeunesse éclatée, by Olga Tarcali, 2000 (Box-folder 344: 3)
  - Torino: Rivista mensile della città e del Piemonte, 1955 (Box-folder 344: 4)
  - The Matchbox, by Mary Peace Finley, 1995 (Box-folder 344: 5)
- Aurora Foundation and Amnesty International files, 1975-1999
  - AIUSA Board of Directors internal documents, 1986-1987, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 345: 1-2)
  - AIUSA task force lists, 1999 (Box-folder 345: 3)
  - Addresses and notes, 1990s (Box-folder 345: 4)
  - Clippings, 1987-1999 (Box-folder 345: 5)
  - Patria indipendente, 1975 December (Box-folder 345: 6)
  - Glasnost, 1990 January-March (Box-folder 345: 7)
  - Notes, address lists, and holiday cards received, 1990s (Box-folder 346: 1)
  - Research material and correspondence relating to Vietnam, 1970s (Box-folder 346: 2)
  - Bibliographical research on Vietnam, 1986 (Box-folder 346: 3)
  - AIUSA board meeting photographs, 1994 October 1 (Box-folder 346: 4)
  - AIUSA board of directors list, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 346: 5)
  - Clippings, 1981-1996 (Box-folder 346: 6-7)
  - Notebooks, 1980s (Box-folder 346: 8)
    Includes GS notes on David Lynch's "The Elephant Man"
  - Human rights printed matter, mainly on Vietnam, 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 346: 9)
  - Leonard Sagan file, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 346: 10)
    Mainly correspondence relating to AI's medical committee
  - Ginetta Sagan Fund, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 346: 11)
  - AIUSA internal documents, circa 1973, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 346: 12)
  - AI medical committee, correspondence and reports, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 347: 1-4)
  - AIUSA internal documents, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 347: 5-6)
  - Aurora Foundation routine correspondence, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 347: 7)
  - Ralph E. Bonin correspondence, mainly on Vietnam, 1979 (Box-folder 347: 8)
  - Barbara Piasecka Johnson correspondence, 1993 (Box-folder 347: 9)
  - Women's International Center Woman of the Year awards, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 347: 10)
    Relates to award for Barbara Piasecka Johnson
  - Biographical clippings, 1996, undated (Box-folder 347: 11)
  - Human rights clippings and printed matter, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 347: 12-13)
  - Vietnam research materials, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 348: 1-3)
  - Amnesty International appeals for action, 1984 (Box-folder 348: 4)
  - Heidi Bradner photographs of mass graves, probably in Chechnia, 1995 (Box-folder 348: 5)
  - Amnesty International internal correspondence, 1977 (Box-folder 349: 1)
  - AIUSA internal correspondence and printed matter, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 349: 2)
  - AIUSA internal documents, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 349: 3)
    Includes development audit
  - Aurora Foundation correspondence and press releases mainly on Vietnam, 1988-1996 (Box-folder 349: 4)
  - Human rights clippings, 1977, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 349: 5-7)
- Biographical clippings, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 349: 8)
- Personal correspondence, letters of gratitude, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 349: 9-10)
  Includes letter from Rose Styron.
- United Nations reports related to rape in the former Yugoslavia, particularly Serbia, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 349: 11)
- Gli ultimi tempi di un regime, by Ildefonso Schuster, 1960 (Box-folder 349: 12)
- Human rights printed matter, 1973-1993 (Box-folder 349: 13)
- Address books, 1970s-1980s (Box-folder 350: 1)
- Date books, 1972-1986
  - 1972-1976, 1979 (Box-folder 350: 2)
    Includes GS's driver's license
  - 1981 (Box-folder 350: 3)
  - 1985 (Box-folder 350: 4)
  - 1986 (Box-folder 350: 5)
- Travel log, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 350: 6)
- Calendars and notes, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 351: 1-2)
- Notebooks, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 351: 3-6)
- Computer disks, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 351: 7)
  Four 3.5" floppy disks containing Ginetta Sagan's memoirs. See Digital files
- Aurora Foundation letters received, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 351: 8-10)
  Relates mainly to Readers Digest article
- Christmas cards received, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 351: 11-12)
- Maps of reeducation camps in the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, 1987 (Map case)
- Sound recordings, 1975, 1983
  - Through the Eyes of Music: Yul Anderson in Concert, 1983 (Record cabinet)
    12" vinyl record
  - Where's My Apple Pie? by Joan Baez, 1975 (Record cabinet)
    7" vinyl record
- Video tapes, 1985
  - "Poland,", November 1985 (Tape cabinet)
    Betacam tape
  - "Sky at Westminster Abbey,", 1985 (Tape cabinet)
    U-Matic tape
- Digital files, 1986-2006
  - GS interview transcripts, 1986-1993 (Computer workstation)
    Mainly on World War II
    - 1986 March 14
      Arthur Goldberg and Philip Geyelin
    - 1989 May 23-August 7
      Nancy Flowers
    - 1991 June 18
      Jeff McNish
    - 1993 March 17-18
      James Baldwin and Loring Sagan
  - Writings by GS, 1990s (Computer workstation)
    - "School days"
    - "Alexander"
    - "Aosta"
    - "August 1943"
    - "Bormio, February 1945"
    - "Remembering February 1945"
    - "July, 1943"
    - "Lidia"
    - "Guido and Nino"
    - "November, 1944"
    - "September 7, 1943"
    - "August-September 8, 1943"
    - "September 8, 1943"
    - "A Stupid Way to Die,", 1987 October
    - Transcript 1A, undated
      On GS's experiences during World War II
    - Transcripts 2-4, undated
      On GS's accident in Poland
  - Writings by others, 1991, 1993 (Computer workstation)
    - Joan Baez poem, "Ginetta,", 1993 January 30
    - Leonard Sagan, "A Sentimental Journey,", 1991 July 5
  - Miscellany, 1994, 2006 (Computer workstation)
    - Aurora Foundation bills from Jeff McNish, 1994 January-March
    - History of the Ginetta Sagan Fund award, 2006 December 10